Curriculum Vitae



Ms.Jaya Arune

Tender Manager/Commercial Manager

An experienced Tender & Commercial Manager with over 12 years of expertise in Manufacturing and Service Industry. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success. Possesses strengths in ownership and dedication, motivated to lead, grow, and excel in the work.

Location: Thane (West), Mumbai

Contact no.:+919082264996

Email id: jayaarune5@gmail.com

Professional Work Experience:

1. Position - Tender Manager

Company - Square Panda Education Private Limited, Andheri

Period - April 2022 to Present

Job Profile:

- End-to-end ownership of bid cycle, supporting sales team for bid management.
- Coordination of tender reviews and deadlines, adjusting them to customer frameworks.
- Effective liaison, support, and assistance between tender process departments.
- Utilizing agreed systems to manage tender process functions, analysis, and documentation.
- Assisting in the development and preparation of the organization's tender process strategy and business planning.

- Techno-Commercial study of tenders, understanding eligibility criteria (PQ, TQ), and scope of work, raising clarifications.
- Attending client meetings, pre-bid meetings, and discussions with clients, providing convincing responses to their questions.
- Managing the clarification of bid conditions and tender preparation.
- Monitoring bid management to align it with the organization's requirements.
- Preparing and submitting Techno-Commercial Proposals to clients and ensuring proper and timely submission of Tenders/Bids/RFPs.
- Responding to post-bid techno-commercial queries for all domestic projects.
- Understanding future business trends and maintaining competitors' track records.
- Handling EMD/SD submission to the Government department in the form of Performance Bank Guarantee and record-keeping for refund collection upon tender finalization.

2. Position - Tender Manager

Company - Eagle Security & Personnel Services, Goregaon

Period - July 2019 to March 2022 (2 Years 8 months)

Job Profile:

- Participating in All India Tenders, assisting the team in preparing Technical and Financial documents required for tender submission.
- Preparing rate approval statements based on the last purchase rate (rate analysis / costing).
- Preparation of Pre-Bid Queries (Technical Deviations & Commercial Deviations/Comments).
- Ensuring projects are executed according to the designed specification, safety requirements, budgeted cost, and schedule.
- Attending Pre-Bid and Negotiation meetings with customers.
- Coordinating post-bid payment follow-up and responding to queries/clarifications.
- Reviewing information about demands and deriving supply and proposal preparations.
- Working on tender contract agreements, EMD refund, and BG release from respective banks.
- Handling clarification on bid conditions/deviations and monitoring the tender preparation.
- Conducting Market Surveys and Site Surveys for Tendering and Bidding.
- Preparing comprehensive Site visit reports, Rate Analysis, Tender Feasibility, Risk Evaluation, Bid Coordination.
- Coordinating with various departments like Finance, Logistics for completion of quality tenders.

- Managing the Tender Team (Executives and Area/Zone Officers) and working closely towards implementing/executing work.
- Important Clients worked with: MCGM and MMRDA Mumbai, Homi Bhabha Mumbai, President's Secretariats New Delhi, APHO New Delhi, Dena Bank all over, Bank of Baroda Jodhpur, Axis Bank all over, Canara Bank Mumbai, North Maharashtra University, etc.

3. Position - Commercial Manager

Company - Responsive Industries Limited, Churchgate

Period - July 2011 to March 2019 (8 Years)

Job Profile:

- Overall responsible for Government tenders & manufacturing business-related activities.
- Registration & approvals in government organizations like Indian Railways (IREPS), RDSO, GEM, and Indian Navy for PVC Vinyl Flooring & Leather Cloth products.
- Coordinating & attending technical meetings with customers.
- Monitoring new tenders, new projects, and general trends, preparing techno-commercial offers, and submitting bids against tenders.
- Handling Govt., Semi-Govt., PSU Sector tenders, and portals for tender submission work.
- Communicating with government officers for modification/Amendments of PO, Payment Clearance, and handling client grievances to preserve the reputation.
- Coordinating with Factory QA people and resolving order-related issues. Handling the Inspection process with third-party organizations like RITES Ltd Mumbai/RDSO Lucknow.
- Assigning delivery schedules for the production team and getting the material procured within the given delivery period.
- Monitoring the logistic department for proper dispatch of the material at the consignee end, then arranging zone officers to supervise the unloading of material at railway workshops/depots.
- Achieving the weekly target of payment collection and recovery against the dispatches.
- Handling all India team of East/West/North/South zone and distributing work accordingly.
- Built strong work relationships with customers, including Indian Navy, Army, All Indian Railways, Shipping
 Corporation of India(SCI), Mazagaon Dock Ltd, ONGC, BEML, and many more Government Projects and
 Government undertaking Projects.

4. Position - Back Office Assistant

Company - Lucky Forms Pvt. Ltd, Vikhroli

Period - April 2009 to June 2011 (2 years 2 months)

Job Profile:

- Checking and replying to emails of Marketing Director.
- Preparing quotations in E-Secretary for printing jobs.
- Coordinating with customers for order and payment.
- Submission of tenders on Railway's online portal (IREPS).
- Preparing inspection documents against the inspection of material.
- Submission of IC (Inspection Certificates) to customers for payment clearance.
- Creation of sales orders and job cards of received orders in ERP software.
- Utilizing E-Secretary software for preparing letters.
- Taking dictation from the Director and sending letters to concerned departments.
- Handling the backend process of Marketing Director.

Educational Qualifications:

Examination	<u>Institute</u>	University/Board	<u>YearofCompletion</u>	Percentage
DCDDM	NIN AIN AC	NIN AIN AC	A	
PGDBM	NMIMS	NMIMS	Appearing	-
B.Com	KirtiCollege	Mumbai University	2009	69.28%
H.S.C	KirtiCollege	MumbaiUniversity	2005	49.83%
S.S.C	I.E.S.School	Maharashtra Board	1999	54.00%

Technical qualification:

Diploma in Computer Hardware & Networking from Jetking Infotrain, Batch of Nov 2007

Achievements:

- Wining Sports-Kabbadi in Inter School competition
- Participated at college Fashion Show
- Participated in Dance in College youth festival

<u>Skills</u>

- Tender Management
- Bid Strategy Development
- Risk Assessment and Mitigation
- Contract Negotiation
- Cross-Functional Collaboration
- Client Relationship Management

Personal detail:

- Date of Birth: 25thOctober1987
- Gender : Female
- Marital Status : Single
- Nationality : Indian
- Languages Known: English, Hindi and Marathi
- Hobbies: Listening Music, Dancing, Photography and Cooking
- Address : Flat no. 12, Bldg No.5, Vijay Vilas Co-Op Society, Anand Nagar, Kavesar, Thane (W) 400607

Declaration:

I hereby declare that information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 3rd August 2023

Place: Mumbai (Ms. Jaya Arune)